Abdul Raafay Shahid

14 Carr Manor Walk | Leeds, LS17 5DN | (+44) 07802805827 | rraf@tuta.io

Links

raafay.world/projects
github.com/rraafays

Technologies

Rust
Java
C#
Typescript
Javasript
Python
C
C++

Languages

English: Native
Spanish: Intermediate
Urdu: Beginner
Punjabi: Beginner

Passions

Martial Arts, Muay Thai, Cooking, Painting, Technology Restoration, Motor Mechanics, Digital Minimalism

Education

BEng Software Engineering Sheffield Hallam University 2020 - present

A-Level Computer Science (C), Maths (C), Economics (D)

Notre Dame Catholic Sixth Form College 2018 - 2020

GCSE Computer Science (A*), Maths (7), English (6 5), Combined Science (6 5), Geography (6), Spanish (5), IT (B) Allerton High School 2013 - 2018

About

Raafay "Raf" Shahid is a passionate and versatile software engineer with a deep-rooted love for programming that began at the age of 13. Raf is a confident and sociable individual with a strong technical foundation and a broad range of interests.

Outside of software engineering, Raf has been practicing Muay Thai for over a year, enjoys cooking both at home and professionally, and has a long-standing passion for painting. He also restores vintage and modern technology and is learning motor mechanics from his father. Committed to digital minimalism, Raf ensures a balanced and focused approach to both his personal and professional life.

Notable Projects

FRMWRK: reproducible laptop system

September 2024

Doro: pomodoro timer written in rust

July 2023

Socks: multi-threaded socket based chat

January 2023

SHU Bank: small-scale online banking

November 2022

Personal Website: projects & passions showcase

July 2022

SHUber: Uber-inspired taxi application

February 2020

Work Experience

Placement Software Engineer: Cognitran Limited

August 2023 - August 2024

Pizza Chef: Ecco Pizzeria

August 2022 - February 2023

Voluntary Technician: AALFY

August 2021 - December 2022

Front of House: Friesday

August 2021 - July 2022